Hi. Ah, my name is Dan, I work on the React
Team and this is my first time in React
Conf. [Applause] And so Sophie talked about these
problems that I think most of you have
encountered in React development. And of
course we could approach these problems
one by one, so we could try to solve them
in isolation. But it seems like solving
one of them makes some other one worse.
So for example, if we try to solve the
wrapper hell by putting more logic into
components themselves, then our
components become larger and harder to
refactor. And then on the other hand, if
we try to split the components apart
into smaller pieces and reuse those, then
we end up with more nests than in the
component tree and we get the wrapper
hell again. And finally in either case we
have all the confusion that comes with
the classes. So we think that this is
because these are not three separate
problems. We think that this is, ah, these are
three symptoms of one problem. And the
problem is that React does not provide a
simpler, smaller, lightweight primitive to
add state or lifecycle than a class
component. And so once you add a class
component, you can split it up further
without introducing the wrapper hell. And
in fact it's not a new problem. So if you
use React for like more than a couple of
years, you might remember then when React
came out it actually included a solution
to this problem. Ah, it was mixins. So
mixins allow you to reuse some methods
between classes and this way you
wouldn't have all these wrappers. So
should we add mixins back to React? [Yeah ... No...]
That's right, no no, we're not gonna do
that. Ah, I mean the codes using mixins
the rounds, it's not like, it's not broken.
But we don't encourage using mixins in
React. And if you curious why there is a
blog post, uh, that we wrote code called
"Mixins Considered Harmful" on the React
Blog, where we explain that we think in
our experience, the problems that mixins
create are worse than the problems that
they solve. Ah, so that's why we don't
encourage using mixins. So perhaps we
could just can't solve this problem
maybe its inherent to the React
component model. Maybe we should just
accept it. [Laughing] Or maybe in there is a, perhaps
there is a different way we could write
our components that doesn't suffer from
either of these problems. And that's what
I'm going to talk about today. But before
I start I want to touch a little bit on
the way we approach making changes and
additions to React which is a year ago
we set up an RFC process, so RFC stands
for request for comments, and it means
that whenever we want to make or
somebody else wants to make a
substantial change or addition to React,
they need to write up a proposal with
detail in the motivation and the
detailed design of how this will work.
And so that's what we're going to do.
We're excited to announce that we are
ready to present a proposal for how we
can solve these three problems.
And importantly this proposal does not
have breaking changes or deprecations in
it. It is strictly additive, it is opt-in,
and it adds some new APIs which happens
when they try to solve problems. And we
would love to hear your feedback on this
proposal which is why we're, ur, we're going
to publish it today. And we thought about
many ways we could share this proposal,
so maybe we just like write off in there ...
write up an RFC and post it. Um, but since we
were going to run React Conf anyway, we
just decided to, ah, just show it here. And
we're going to demo.
[Applause]
It already mirrors the displays. Sorry,
technical glitch.
Ur, can somebody who understands projectors
help me. [Laughing] Ur, can I make it mirror my desktop?
Please.
(I can do it) Yeah. [Laughing]
Okay but it doesn't show on the screen, I
don't see anything. [Laughing]
That's, that's the problem that I had.  [Applause]
Okay, disaster averted. [Laughing]
All right, um, let me check the font size a
little bit. Do you see this file? [Yeah] All right.
So, ah, here is a simple React component, ah, that
just it is a row, this is just some
styling, and it it renders a person's
name. And so let's say that we want this
name to be editable. So how do you do it
in React normally? Well, like if we want
to add an input there we need to return
this component into a class, add some
local state to it, and let that state
drive the input. So that's exactly what
I'm going to do, uh, that's what we do today.
So I'm gonna do the export default class
Greeding extends React component. And so
I'm going to use only stable javaScript
syntax. So constructor props, super props.
This the state, going to initialize, ur,
name to Mary here. And I'm going to
declare a render method and copy and
paste this.
Sorry.
Okay. And so I want this to be instead of
just rendering the name, I want this
render an input. So I'm replacing
this by an input, and the value of the
input is this dot state dot name. And
if I make a change I want to call this
dot handleNameChange, that's going to
be my change caller. And I'm going to
declare it here, when the name changes we
call setState like we normally do. And
we set the name to e dot target dot
value. Right. So now if I edit the ... [TypeError In Page] Okay so
I, I need to bind ... [Laughing] Sorry I need to bind
the events on there. Okay so now I can
actually edit it and it works. So a
familiar class component is, uh, if you work
with React probably right a lot of
those. But let's take a step back. What if
we didn't have to write a class when we
wanted to use state. So I'm not sure how
that's gonna work. But I'll just start
with what I know, I want to render an
input. So I'm gonna put an input here. And
the input has a value and that value
is the current name, so I'll just pass
name. I don't know where to get name from.
So it doesn't come from props, uh,
I'll just declare it, and I don't know,
I'll fill it in later. Uh, it's gonna have a
change caller there as well, so I'm going
to declare onChange handleNameChange.
And I'm adding a function here takes an
event. And then here I want to tell React
to set the name to something, but again
I'm not sure how to do that from a
functional component. So I'll just call
something called setName.
With the current input value. And I'll
just declare it here.
All right, so these two things they're
closely related, right. So one of them is
the current value of the name state
variable and the other is a function
that lets us set the name state variable.
And so because these things are closely
related, I'm actually going to put them
together as a pair of values. So I'm
going to get them together from
somewhere. So where do I get them from?
From React local state. So how do I use
React local state from a function
component? Well, what if I could just use
state.
And past the initial state to specify it.
Let's see if this works. Yeah, it works.
[Applause & Cheers]
So let's, let's compare the two
approaches. So on the left we have a
familiar class component. This state has
to be an object. Uh, we bind some event
handlers so that we can access. This
inside the event handler for this dot setState.
When we call setState it
actually doesn't just set the state that
merges, the state are the argument into
the state object. And then when we want
to access the state which is this dot
state dot something. So in the
example on the right, we don't need to
access this dot state dot something.
Because the name state variable is
already available in the function. It's
just the variable. And similarly when we
need to set the state, we don't need to
access this dot something. Because the
function that let us set the name is
also available in the scope. So what is
useState exactly? UseState is a hook. A
hook is a function provided by React
that lets you hook into React features
from your function components. And
useState is the first hook that we're going
to take a look at today, but there are a
few more. So we're going to see them
later.
All right, so let's go back to our
familiar class example. So let's say we
wanted to add a second field. For example,
for a surname. So the way we normally do
this is we add another key to the state.
And we, uh, I'm going to copy and paste this
row. It's gonna say surname now. It's
going to render a surname, and handleSurnameChange.
When I copy and paste
this event handler, this will be surname.
And I need to bind it.
Okay, Mary Poppins. So we can see that it
works. Uh, so how do we do the same with
hooks? So one thing we could do is we
could make our state an object. As you
can see that the state with hooks state
doesn't have to be an object. It can be
any primitive. We could make it an object
if we wanted to, but we also don't have
to. So conceptually surname is, uh, is not
closely related to state, uh, to the name. So
what we could do is we could declare a
second state variable by calling the
useState hook again.
So I'll declare surname. I can give it any
name, it's just the variable in my code.
And setSurname. Calling useState and
passing the initial state for that state
variable 'Poppins'.
So again I'm gonna copy and paste
the row. Say surname, the value surname,
handleSurnameChange. And when the user
edits the surname, not sir name, we want
to set the surname.
Let's see if this works.
Yay, it looks like it works. [Applause]
So we can see that we can use hooks more
than once in a component. Let's compare
the two approaches in more detail. So on
the left familiar class component state
is always an object, has multiple fields,
may call setState will merge some
something into that object. And then when
we want to access it, we do this dot
state dot something. On the right in the
example using hooks, we use the state
hook twice. And that declares two state
variables: name and surname. And whenever
we call setName or setSurname,
this tells React that it needs to
rerender this component, just like if we
called setState. And so the next time
React renders our components is going
to pass the current name and the current
surname to our component. And then we can
use it directly without accessing this
dot state dot something.
All right. So let's go back to our class
example. What else, what other features of
React we know? So another thing you
might want to do from a component is to
read context. So context, in case you're
not familiar, it's like, ur, kind of like
global variables for a subtree. So it's
useful for things like read the current
theme like visual theme or the current
language that the user is using. And it's
useful to avoid passing everything
through props if you need all components
to be able to read some value. So we're
going to import ThemeContext and
LocaleContext which I already declared in
another file. And the API you've probably
most familiar with for consuming context,
especially if you have to consume
multiple contexts, is the render prop API.
And it looks like this. So I'm going to
scroll down here. So we can choose ThemeContext
Consumer that gives us the theme.
In my case, it's just going to be a CSS
class. So I copy this, all this code
inside the render prop. And I'm going to
use className equals 'theme' . All right,
very old-timey. [Laughing]
And I also want to show the current
language, so I'm going to use
LocaleContext Consumer. And it's going to
render another row, so I will copy and
paste this row, can say language.
Language. And render it here. Okay, we can
see that context works. And that's
probably normally consume context. We
actually added a more convenient API for
accessing it in classes in 16.6. Ur, but
this is how you can see multiple
contexts. So let's look at the, at how we
could do this with hooks. So as we said
that, state is a fundamental feature of
React and this is why you can use state.
And so if we want to use context, I need
to import my contexts. So this is gonna
be a ThemeContext, LocaleContext. And
now if I want to use context from my
component, I can use context. And then to
get the current theme, I can use context
ThemeContext. And to get the current
locale I can use context LocaleContext.
And this doesn't just read the context,
it also subscribes the component to
updates to this context. But it just
gives me the current values, so I can, I
can put it into my CSS className. And I
can add the bro, that's language, and I can
put it here.
[Applause]
那么，让我们，让我们比较这两个
方法。这是传统的
render prop API 的使用方式。
非常清楚地显示了它正在做什么。
但是它还包含了一点点的
嵌套，而且你遇到的不只有
任何一种
render prop API。所以使用 hooks，它
也能做同样的事情。但是会有些单调。所以我们
就说我们使用这个 context 在这个
context 中，并且我们得到了 theme 和 locale。
然后我们可以使用它们了。然后，你可能
想问 React 是如何
知道的。例如，我在这调用了两个
useState。所以它是如何知道
哪一个 state 和调用的哪一个
useState 是相一致的。答案是
React 依赖于这些
调用的顺序。这可能有一点不太寻常。
为了让它正确地运行起来。
当你在使用 hooks 的时候，这儿有一条你需要去遵循的规则。
这条规则就是
你不能在条件里面调用 hook。
它必须在你的组件的顶层。
所以如果我做一些类似于
props 条件，然后我在这调用 useState
hook。我们实际上拥有一个
linter 插件用来提示
'This is not the correct way to use
hooks'。我们意识到这是一个
不同寻常的限制，嗯，但是这对正确地使用
hooks 十分重要，也
可以使事情变得更明确，我
认为你们会喜欢它的，我等会儿会向你们
展示它。
那么，让我们回头看看我们的 class。
你使用 class 想要
达到的另一件事可能就是生命周期
方法。所以最普遍的
生命周期方法的案例就是你想要
执行一些 sideEffect，例如发送
请求，执行一些
使用浏览器 API 的必要的 DOM 转换接口
所以，你可能想要
做一些类似于这个，但是你不能使用
渲染。因为它还不能
被渲染。所以，你在 React 中使用
side effects 的方法是你声明一个
类似于 componentDidMount 的生命周期方法。
那么比如说，嗯，让我向你们展示一下
这个。那么，你看到在屏幕的顶部，
它显示的是 React App。这里实际上拥有一个
使我们更新这个的浏览器 API。
比如说我们想要这个 tab 的标题变成
这个人的名字并且随着我定义的值而改变。
然后，现在我要初始化它
嗯，这儿有一个浏览器 API 可以做
这件事，那就是 document.title 等于
this.state.name 加空格加
this.state.surname。那么现在我们可以
看见这里显示 Mary Poppins。但是如果我现在，
如果我编辑它，它不会
自动地更新，因为我也
需要 implement componentDitUpdate。
为了让 side effect 变得
和我渲染的一致，所以我
将要声明 componentDitUpdate,
就只要复制和粘贴到这。
那么，现在说 Mary Poppins，但是如果我
开始编辑它，这个文档的标题也更新了。
这就是我们如何在一个
class 里执行一个 side effect 了。
所以我们要如何用 hooks 实现它呢。
执行 side effect 是
React 组件的另一个核心特点。
所以如果我们想要使用我们的
组件的效果，需要从 React 里 import 一个 useEffect。
然后我们要告诉 React
在 React 清除组件之后
对 DOM 做什么。所以我们通过一个
在我们执行 effect 的时候的函数
所以我设置 document.
title 等于 name 加上空格加上
surname。你们可以看到这儿就显示了 Mary Poppins。
然后如果我开始编辑它，它实际上也会
更新。
所以要使默认的 userEffect 运行起来
需要在初始化渲染和每一次
更新之后。所以通过默认设置他会和
这儿渲染什么相一致。
如果出于考虑性能原因
或者你有特殊的逻辑，可以选择不采用这种行为。
在我之后，Ryan 的演讲
将会谈到一些关于这个的内容。所以，让我们
比较这两个方法。在这个，这个
类里，我们将函数分开。我们
基于生命周期函数名将逻辑分开。所以
这是我们为什么会有 componentDidMount,
componentDitUpdate 的原因。他们在
不同的时间上被触发。我们有时候
在他们之间重复一些逻辑。我们可以把
它放进一个函数里，但是我们仍然不得不
在两个地方调用它，而且要记得
保持一致。通过，通过使用
effect hook，效果会和
默认的保持一致。即使这有个办法
能够不采用这个方法。并不是说
在类中我们需要访问 this.state，
所以需要一个特殊的 API 来完成
这个。但是在这个 effect 例子中，我们
实际上不需要一个特殊的 API 去
访问这个 state
变量。因为它已经在
这个函数的范围内。它被声明在
右边。这就是 the effect
被声明在这个 component 里，而
不是，不是在外面的原因。因为
这样我们能够访问 state 变量，
能够去设置他们和任何其他
像当前上下文的值。例如，
这些上下文的其中一个。
那么，我们回头看看熟悉的
类的例子。嗯，其他你可能
想要做的事是使用生命周期方法
在类被使用的时候。所以你可能想要
去订阅一些浏览器 API，
然后它会提供给你一些值，例如
窗口的大小。然后你想要更新
这个 state 对该值的改变做出反应。
所以我们可以在一个类里使用这个方法
比如说我们想要，嗯，
我们想要监测窗口的宽度。所以
我将 width 放进 state 里。这个
window.innerWidth 浏览器 API。然后我
想要渲染它。嗯，让我们复制并且粘贴
这个。所以这个将会展示 width。我将
在这个地方渲染它。它是 this.state
width。这就是窗口的宽度了，
而不是 Mary Poppins 的宽度。 [大笑]
我将添加一个，嗯，我将要添加
一个事件监听，所以我们需要真真切切地
监听这个 width 的改变。所以设置
window.addEventListener。
我，我将监听 resize 事件，
handleResize。然后我需要
声明这个事件。所以在这儿
我们将更新这个 width 状态，变成
window.innerWidth。然后我们需要
去绑定它。然后，嗯，然后我也需要
取消订阅。所以我不想要一个内存
泄漏比如说保留这些
订阅。我想要从这个事件取消订阅。
所以我们在一个类里做这个的办法
是我们创建其他
叫做 componentWillUnmount 的生命周期方法。然后
我将复制并且粘贴这段逻辑逻辑代码
到这，将这个替换成
removeEventListener。所以我们设置了一个事件
监听，然后我们移除这个事件
监听。然后我们可以
通过拖动来验证这一点。你看到
这个 width 正在变化。所以它起效果了。所以
让我们看看如何可以，我们如何
用 hooks 实现这个。因此，从概念上来说，监听
窗口宽度
与设置文档标题无关。所以这就是为什么
我们没有把它放入 effect 的原因。
这在概念上是完全独立的 effect，
就像我们可以使用不止一次的 useState 用来
去声明多种 state
变量，我们可以使用不止一次的 useEffect
去实现不同的 side effects。
所以我想要订阅 window.
addEventListener，resize，handleResize。然后
我需要保存一些
当前 width 的状态。
所以，我将声明其他的
state 变量。所以我提到，嗯，width 和
setWidth。我们通过 useState
设置他们的初始值为 window.innerWidth。
现在，在我的 handleResize 函数里,
我将在这声明它。因为它
没有在其他地方被使用。然后用
setWidth 去设置它当前的 width。嗯，我
需要去渲染它。所以我复制
并粘贴这个 row。我在这儿写 width。
最后我需要在这个
effect 之后去清除它。所以我需要指定如何
清除。再一次从概念上说，清除
也是这个 effect 的一部分。所以这个 effect
有一个清除的地方。这个顺序，你，
你可以提出的办法是任何
effect 可以选择返回一个函数。
如果它返回一个函数，那么
React 将调用这个函数
在 effect 之后清除。所以这就是我们
取消订阅的地方。
Ok，让我们验证一下
这个实际的操作吧。耶！[鼓掌]
那么让我们比较这两个方法。在左边，我们使用了一个
熟悉的 class 组件，嗯，在这没有
令人惊喜的东西。我们，我们有一些 side
effects，一些和逻辑相关的是分开
的部分。所以我们可以看见文档的标题
在这儿被设置。但是它在这也
被设置了。然后我们在这订阅一个
effect。
抱歉，在这订阅这个事件，但是我们
在这取消订阅。所以这些事情需要
相互同步。然后这个
方法包含了两个不相关的方法
在这不相关的两行中。因此，我，在，在
特点上孤立地测试他们有点难。
但是它看起来非常的令人熟悉。
所以，这，这很棒。所以这段
代码看起来可能会更不怎么熟悉。但是
让我们再看一看这里发生了什么。
嗯，在 hooks 中，我们分离代码
不是基于生命周期函数的名字，
而是基于这段代码要做什么。所以
我们可以看到这个有一个 effect
我们用来更新文档的标题
这是一件 compnent 能做的事。
然后这儿有另一个
被订阅用于 window resize 时间的 effect
并且当它被改变时在这个 state 里被更新。
然后，嗯，这个 effect 有一个清除
阶段，意味着什么时候该去
移除这个 effect，React 移除它
然后避免内存泄漏。如果你
一直仔细观察，你可能注意到
由于 effect 在每次渲染之后运行，
我们只是继续重新订阅。所以
这儿有一个方法去优化这个。嗯。所以
默认是一致的，嗯，这
很重要。如果你，例如在这使用一些
prop，我需要去重新注册一个不同的 id
从道具或类似的东西。但是这儿有
一个方法去优化它并且选择不用这个
行为。然后 Ryan 在下一个
演讲中将会提到如何去实现它。
All right, so there is one more thing that I want
to show here. So this component is
getting pretty large, and it's fine. So we
expect that since you now can do more in
function components, they will get larger
and that's totally okay. Um, but you might
want to reuse some of that logic in
other components or extract it or test
it separately. What's interesting though
is that hooks calls uh, they are just
function calls. And components they are
just functions. So how do you share your
logic between two functions? You extract
it to a different function. That's what
I'm going to do. You're going to copy and
paste this. And I'm going to create a new
function called useWindowWidth and I'll
just paste it here. And so we need the
width in our component in order to
render it. So I need to return it from
this function, which is the current width.
And then I can go back up. And I can say
const width equals useWindowWidth.
[Applause]
[Cheers]
So what is this function? We didn't do
anything special, we just extracted the
function. Uh, but there is a convention here.
So we are calling this function a custom
hook. And by convention custom hook names
always start with use. And so there are
two reasons for this. We're now going to
like read your function name or to
string it or anything like this. But it
is an important convention because first
of all, this lets us lint automatically
for violation of the first rule that I
described about call hooks unconditionally.
So if we didn't know if something is a
hook, then we wouldn't be able to do that.
And another reason is that if you just
look at the component code, you kind of
want to know if some function can have
some state inside of it. So it's
important that there is a convention is
, okay, use something it means that it's
potentially stateful. And here width gives
us the current width and subscribes us to
updates through it. So if we wanted to, we
could even go further. It's probably not
necessary in this example, but I just
want to give you like a sense of what
you could do. Um, so let's say like maybe
setting the document title was a bit
more complicated and you wanted to like
extract it or test it separately. So I
could just copy and paste this. and I
could write a new custom hook. I'm gonna
call this one useDocumentTitle. And so
the name and surname don't really make
sense in the scope's context. We just want
to call this title. And this is going to
be an argument, so custom hooks are
javascript functions, so they can take
arguments and return values or not
return. So it is going to take title as
an argument. And now in my component, I
can say useDocumentTitle, name plus
surname.
In fact, I could go even further. So in
this case it's totally unnecessary, but
again, maybe our inputs were more
complicated, maybe we were tracking
whether the input was focused and
blurred, whether it has been validated,
submitted and so on. So maybe we had some
more logic there we wanted to pull it
out of our components. Um, and reduce
duplication. And there is already some
duplication, so we have this like almost
identical event handlers. So what if we
could just, um, I'm going to delete one of
them and extract the other one. I'm going
to create a new hook, that I'm going to
call useFormInput. So this is my change
handler. Now I'll also copy and paste
this declaration. So this defines the
state for this input. And so it's no
longer name and setName. I'll just call
generically value and setValue. It's
going to take the initial value as an
argument. And this is just going to be a
handleChange, and this will setValue. So
what do we want to get in order to use
this, uh, use an input in our component? We
want to get the current value, and a
change handler. These are the things that
we attach to the input. So let's just
return them. Um, return value and onChange
handleChange. So now if we go back up, we
can say name equals useFormInput Mary.
The name is going to be an object with
value and onChange fields. And surname
is useFormInput Poppins. So this is now
going to be named dot value and surname
dot value because this is where the
string is. And so now I can remove this,
and I can spread over the name object.
Someone is laughing. [Laughing] All right. Let's just
verify it and break it, yeah it works. So
each time we call a hook, its state is
completely isolated. And this is because
we just rely on the order of hook calls,
and not on names or anything. So you can
call the same hook multiple times. Each
call will get its own local state. So
let's compare the two approaches for
the last time. Um, so on the left we have a
familiar class component, it has some,
some state in an object, bind some
methods, has some logic spread across
different lifecycle methods as a
bunch of event handlers, um, uses, um, uses
something things from the context and
render stuff. Um, pretty familiar. And on the
right pane, this may not look like the
React components were used to. But it
kind of makes sense. Even if you don't
know how these functions are implemented.
You can see okay it uses to form inputs,
uses some context to get theme and
locale, it uses the window width and
document title, and it renders a bunch of
stuff. And if we want to. We can scroll
further and we can see okay, so this is
how the input works, this is how setting
the document title works, this is how the
window width subscription works. Or maybe
this could be an npm package and you
don't actually need to know that. All we
could pull it back into a component or
copy and paste between components. So
hooks give you custom hooks, give you the
flexibility to create your own
abstractions that are not ...  they do not
inflate your React component tree and avoid
the wrapper hell.
[Applause]
And importantly these are not two
separate applications. So this is
actually one application. So I have this
window open just to demonstrate that
classes can work side by side with hooks.
And while hooks represent our vision for
the future of React. Uh, we don't want to
make breaking changes like this. So we
need to keep classes working. Ur, let's go
back to you the slides. All right, now
this is a slider you can actually tweet. [Laughing]
We present the Hooks proposal to you
today.
Uh, hooks let us to use all React features
without having to write a class. They do
not deprecated classes, but you have the
option to not have to write them. We
intend to cover all use cases for
classes with hooks as soon as possible.
There are a few that are missing, but
we're working on them. And hooks let you
reuse stateful logic, extracted out of
components, tested separately, reuse it
between different components without
introducing the wrapper hell. And again
importantly it's not a breaking change,
completely backwards compatible, strictly
addition ..., uh, additive. And you can find the,
we wrote the documentation for hooks, so
you can find it at this url. Um, and
we want to hear from you, the React
community wanna hear what you think
about hooks. Um, whether you like them or not.
And we realize that it's pretty hard to
give feedback without actually trying
them. So we built them, and we released
sixty ..., um, sixteen seven alpha. It's not a
major release, it's a minor release. But
in alpha where you can try hooks. And
we've been trying them in production at
Facebook for about a month. So we don't
expect major bugs there. But the APIs
themselves may change together with your
feedback. And I asked you not to rewrite
anything like not to rewrite their whole
apps with hooks. Because first of all it's,
it's a proposal. And second because
personally I, I find that it takes a bit
of a mind shift to start thinking in
hooks, and it might be a bit confusing if
you try to just take a class component
and convert it. But I do encourage you to
try using hooks in some of the newer
code that you write in and let us know
what you think. So,
thank you.
[Applause]
So in our view hooks represent our
vision for the future of React. But I
think they also represent the way we
move React forward. And that is we don't
do big rewrite. Uh, we want the new patterns
that we like better to coexist with the
old patterns, so that we can have gradual
migration and adoption just like you can
gradually adopt React itself. And this is
almost the end of my talk. Uh, I want to end
it on a personal note. So I started
learning React about four years ago. And
one of my first questions was why JSX.
Uh, but my second one of the next questions
was I can figure out what does the logo
have to do with React. So the project is
not called Atom, it's not a physics
engine.
Um, so one interpretation is that it's kind
of upon on
reactions, so atoms participate in
chemical reactions, reactions -> React. Um, but
it's not a claim with React actually
got it, uh, I found a different interpretation
that made more sense to me. And the way I
think about it, uh,
we know that physical matter consists of
atoms. And we've learned that it's the
types of these atoms and their
properties that determine how the
physical matter looks and behaves. And
React has taught me something similar,
that you can take a user interface and
you can split it into these independent
units called components, and it's the
types and properties of these components
that can describe how the user interface
looks and behaves.
What's ironic though is that the word
'atom', it literally means indivisible. So
when scientists just discovered atom for
the first time, they thought this is the
smallest thing we're gonna find. But
later they discovered an electron, which
is a smaller particle inside the atom.
And it turned out it actually electrons
explain a lot about how atoms work. And I
kind of feel the same way about hooks. I
don't feel like hooks are a new feature.
Rather I feel that hooks provide me with
access to React features that I already
know, such as state and context and lifecycle.
And I feel like hooks are a more
direct representation of React. And that
they really explain how a component
works inside. And I feel like they've
been hiding in plain sight for four
years. And in fact if you look at the
React logo, you can see those electron
orbits there. So maybe hooks have been
there all along. Thank you.
[Applause]
Dan, thank you so much. Sophie thank you
as well.